Inventory of the Kurt Glaser collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Kurt Glaser collection
1945-1970
69035
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Bulletins, press releases, and correspondence relating to Allied military governmental structure in Germany after World War II, governmental structure in Switzerland, the Common Market, Sudeten Germans, and the views of Senator William E. Jenner on American foreign policy.
Glaser, Kurt, 1914-1993, collector.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Bulletins, press releases, reports, and correspondence relating to Allied military governmental structure in Germany after World War II, governmental structure in Switzerland, the Common Market, Sudeten Germans, the views of Senator William E. Jenner on American foreign policy, and drafts of a book on the impact and aftermath of the Commission for Relief in Belgium.
Jenner, William E. (William Ezra), 1908-1985.; European Economic Community.; Administrative law--Germany.; Germans--Czechoslovakia.; Military government.; Germany--History--1945-1955.; Switzerland--Politics and government--20th century.
- Arbeitskreis Sudetendeutscher Jungakademiker, literature reviews, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- European Economic Community (Common Market), 1960-1970 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes press releases, information guides, and articles. In English and French.
- Weinheim Conference, 1950 December 2-3 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  Reports and summaries of the Weinheim Conference by the Institut zur Förderung öffentlicher Angelegenheiten. Also includes a British military personnel form, informational handouts from Der Deutschen Gesellschaft für Personalwesen E.V., and essays by Maurice Lagrange and Dr. Fritz Türk. In German.
- West German federal administration, laws and forms, 1950 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Ausschuss für wirtschaftliche Verwaltung, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  Includes bylaws, correspondence, notes, and reports. In German and English.
- Development of local government in Bavaria, 1945-1950 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  Includes laws, reports, and notes. In German and English.
- Development of local government in west-German states, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  Laws, constitutions, reports, notes, and correspondence. Includes the German states of North Rhine-Westphalia, Hamburg, Rheinland-Palatinate, Lower Saxony, Schleswig-Holstein, and Hesse. In German and English.
- Reports on governmental structure of Switzerland, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Senator William Jenner, foreign policy speeches, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Drafts of book on Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1970
  - Chapter 1 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Chapter 2 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Chapter 3 (Box-folder 2: 3-4)
  - Chapter 4 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Chapter 6 (Box-folder 2: 6)